{"status":"Success","data":{"question_paper1":[{"question_no":"1","question":"\u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d2c\u0d41 1500 \u0d30\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d35\u0d3e\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d4d \u0d35\u0d3e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d3f 1320 \u0d30\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d41. \u0d0e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d28\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30 \u0d36\u0d24\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02?","option1":"10%","option2":"12%","option3":"17%","option4":"13%","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"2","question":"\u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d2a\u0d30\u0d40\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d23\u0d2e\u0d46\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7d 50% \u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d32\u0d2d\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d23\u0d02. \u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d15\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d 172 \u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d15\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d4b\u0d7e 28 \u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7b\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d41\u0d31\u0d35\u0d41\u0d15\u0d4a\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d1c\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32. \u0d0e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d06\u0d15\u0d46 \u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30?","option1":"50","option2":"100","option3":"200","option4":"400","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"3","question":"2000 \u0d30\u0d42\u0d2a \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d38\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3f \u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d15\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d35\u0d1f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d7b 10% \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d32 \u0d35\u0d7c\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d3f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d4d 10% \u0d21\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d\u200c\u0d15\u0d57\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d7d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d41. \u0d0e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d38\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d07\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d4b\u0d34\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d46 \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d46\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d? ","option1":"2010","option2":"1800","option3":"2000","option4":"1980","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"4","question":"10 \u0d38\u0d46\u0d7b\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d40\u0d2e\u0d40\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d7c \u0d28\u0d40\u0d33\u0d02, 6 \u0d38\u0d46\u0d7b\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d40 \u0d2e\u0d40\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d7c \u0d35\u0d40\u0d24\u0d3f, \u0d38\u0d46\u0d7b\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d40 \u0d2e\u0d40\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d7c \u0d09\u0d2f\u0d30\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d1a\u0d24\u0d41\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d43\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d 3 \u0d38\u0d46\u0d7b\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d40 \u0d2e\u0d40\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d7c \u0d35\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30 \u0d17\u0d4b\u0d33\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d7e \u0d05\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f \u0d35\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d02? ","option1":"7","option2":"4","option3":"5","option4":"6","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"5","question":"\u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d38\u0d48\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7e \u0d1a\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 10 \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d31\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d4b\u0d7e 32 \u0d2e\u0d40\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d7c \u0d26\u0d42\u0d30\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d41. \u0d0e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7d 4 \u0d15\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d2e\u0d40\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d7c \u0d26\u0d42\u0d30\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30 \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d31\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d47\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d35\u0d30\u0d41\u0d02?","option1":"125","option2":"12800","option3":"1250","option4":"1280","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"6","question":"\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f 5000 \u0d30\u0d42\u0d2a 20% \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d05\u0d7c\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d37\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d15\u0d42\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d2a\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d36 \u0d15\u0d23\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d47\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d41. \u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d35\u0d7c\u0d37\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d34\u0d3f\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1e\u0d3e\u0d7d \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30 \u0d30\u0d42\u0d2a \u0d24\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d46 \u0d32\u0d2d\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d02?","option1":"6050","option2":"1000","option3":"1050","option4":"6000","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"7","question":"\u0d2e\u0d42\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d02\u0d16\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d15\u0d33\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d36\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d36\u0d30\u0d3f 12 \u0d09\u0d02 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d46 \u0d30\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d02\u0d16\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d15\u0d33\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d36\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d36\u0d30\u0d3f 10 \u0d09\u0d02 \u0d05\u0d35\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d28 \u0d30\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d41 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d16\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d15\u0d33\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d36\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d36\u0d30\u0d3f 14 \u0d09\u0d02 \u0d06\u0d23\u0d46\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d05\u0d35\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d0f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d02\u0d16\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"16","option2":"8","option3":"12","option4":"28","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"8","question":"\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d47\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d05\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d16\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d? 2,7,3,26,4, ..............","option1":"5","option2":"35","option3":"63","option4":"15","answer":"63"},{"question_no":"9","question":"TEACHER\u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d 205138518 \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d30\u0d39\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d15\u0d4b\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d7d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d7d STUDENT \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7b\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d4b\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d?","option1":"192021451420","option2":"19202145120","option3":"192021451520","option4":"192021451320","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"10","question":"\u0d38\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d28 \u0d2c\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d41\u0d15.\nTomorrow : Yesterday :: Saturday : ","option1":"Thursday","option2":"Monday","option3":"Sunday","option4":"Friday","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"11","question":"+ \u0d17\u0d41\u0d23\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 x \u0d38\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d32\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 \u00f7 \u0d35\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d35\u0d15\u0d32\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 - \u0d39\u0d30\u0d23\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d42\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d41\u0d35\u0d46\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7d (18+10x20)-8\u00f76 \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30?","option1":"92","option2":"19","option3":"35","option4":"26","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"12","question":"\u0d38\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d02 12.30 \u0d35\u0d3e\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d42\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d2e\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d42\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d42\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d07\u0d1f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d15\u0d4b\u0d23\u0d33\u0d35\u0d4d \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30 \u0d21\u0d3f\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d?","option1":"160","option2":"110","option3":"165","option4":"180","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"13","question":"\u0d05\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d41\u0d2a\u0d47\u0d7c \u0d12\u0d30\u0d41\u0d35\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d2e\u0d47\u0d36\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d1a\u0d41\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d07\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d15\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d. A \u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d35\u0d32\u0d24\u0d41\u0d35\u0d36\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d30\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3e\u0d2e\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f B \u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 B \u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d07\u0d1f\u0d24\u0d41\u0d35\u0d36\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d42\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d2e\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f C \u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 C \u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d35\u0d32\u0d24\u0d41\u0d35\u0d36\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d30\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3e\u0d2e\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f D \u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 D \u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d35\u0d32\u0d24\u0d41\u0d35\u0d36\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d30\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3e\u0d2e\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f E \u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d07\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d41.","option1":"A","option2":"B","option3":"C","option4":"D","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"14","question":"2012 \u0d1c\u0d28\u0d41\u0d35\u0d30\u0d3f 1 \u0d1e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d34\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d06\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d7d 2013\u0d7d \u0d31\u0d3f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d26\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d06\u0d34\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d02","option1":"\u0d36\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d34\u0d4d\u0d1a","option2":"\u0d35\u0d46\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d34\u0d4d\u0d1a","option3":"\u0d1e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d34\u0d4d\u0d1a","option4":"\u0d35\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d34\u0d3e\u0d34\u0d4d\u0d1a","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"15","question":"A,X\u0d7b\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d39\u0d4b\u0d26\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 X ,Y \u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d2e\u0d15\u0d33\u0d41\u0d02 Y, Z \u0d7b\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d2e\u0d15\u0d33\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d06\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d41. \u0d0e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7d A \u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d Z \u0d28\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d2c\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d02 \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d ?","option1":"\u0d05\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e","option2":"\u0d2a\u0d57\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f","option3":"\u0d05\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d7b","option4":"\u0d05\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1b\u0d7b","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"16","question":"\u0d0f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d41\u0d31\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1e \u0d15\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d33\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d47\u0d30\u0d33\u0d02 \u0d2d\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d2e\u0d41\u0d16\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f?","option1":"\u0d2a\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d02 \u0d24\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d41\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33","option2":"\u0d38\u0d3f.\u0d0e\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d4d. \u0d2e\u0d41\u0d39\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d26\u0d4d \u0d15\u0d4b\u0d2f","option3":"\u0d2a\u0d3f.\u0d15\u0d46.\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d26\u0d47\u0d35\u0d7b \u0d28\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d7c","option4":"\u0d06\u0d7c.\u0d36\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d7c","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"17","question":"'\u0d17\u0d41\u0d30\u0d41\u0d2a\u0d7c\u0d35\u0d4d\u0d35' \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d24\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d18\u0d4b\u0d37\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d38\u0d3f","option2":"\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d16\u0d4d ","option3":"\u0d2c\u0d41\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d27","option4":"\u0d07\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d02","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"18","question":"\u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d7b \u0d30\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d2a\u0d41\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d39\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d30\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d15\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d28 \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d06\u0d30\u0d4d","option1":"\u0d21\u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d41. \u0d0e\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d4d . \u0d15\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d7c ","option2":"\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d35\u0d7d \u0d2e\u0d4b\u0d34\u0d4d\u200c\u0d38\u0d4d ","option3":"\u0d21\u0d3f. \u0d09\u0d26\u0d2f\u0d15\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d7c ","option4":"\u0d39\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d7a ","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"19","question":"\u0d2a\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d41\u0d15\u0d33\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d41\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d36\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40\u0d2f \u0d2a\u0d20\u0d28\u0d02?","option1":"\u0d13\u0d7a\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d4b\u0d33\u0d1c\u0d3f","option2":"\u0d13\u0d21\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4b\u0d33\u0d1c\u0d3f ","option3":"\u0d13\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4b\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3f","option4":"\u0d13\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4b\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d21\u0d3f\u0d2f ","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"20","question":"\u0d15\u0d36\u0d41\u0d35\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f \u0d17\u0d35\u0d47\u0d37\u0d23 \u0d15\u0d47\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f \u0d06\u0d28\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d2f\u0d02 \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d1c\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d15\u0d4a\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d02","option2":"\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d","option3":"\u0d35\u0d2f\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d","option4":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d41\u0d31\u0d02","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"21","question":"'\u0d2a\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d39\u0d02' \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d17\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d39\u0d02 \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d1a\u0d4a\u0d35\u0d4d\u0d35","option2":"\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d42\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4b","option3":"\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d38\u0d4d","option4":"\u0d36\u0d41\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d7b","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"22","question":"\u0d10\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d39\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7b\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d40\u0d2f \u0d15\u0d33\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d?\r\n","option1":"\u0d1c\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d7b","option2":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d21","option3":"\u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f","option4":"\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7b","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"23","question":"'\u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d21\u0d4b' \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d1c\u0d40\u0d35\u0d3f \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":" \u0d15\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d35\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d","option2":"\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f","option3":"\u0d2a\u0d47\u0d7b","option4":"\u0d15\u0d4a\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7b\u0d1a\u0d46\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d3f","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"24","question":"\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d2a\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d0f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d42\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d24\u0d7d \u0d15\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d35\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d15\u0d02 \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d28\u0d48\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d1c\u0d7b ","option2":"\u0d39\u0d48\u0d21\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d1c\u0d7b","option3":"\u0d13\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d1c\u0d7b","option4":"\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d7b","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"25","question":"\u0d15\u0d47\u0d30\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7b\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f \u0d15\u0d25\u0d15\u0d33\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d30\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d41?","option1":"\u0d15\u0d47\u0d30\u0d33\u0d28\u0d1f\u0d28\u0d02","option2":"\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d2e\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d02","option3":"\u0d15\u0d43\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d23\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d02 ","option4":"\u0d06\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d25","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"26","question":"\u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d1c\u0d40\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d48\u0d2e\u0d47\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d41\u0d15\u0d33\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d0f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d2d\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d42\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d ","option1":"\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d7b\u0d38\u0d3f","option2":"\u0d17\u0d4b\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32","option3":"\u0d12\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d09\u0d1f\u0d3e\u0d7b","option4":"\u0d2e\u0d28\u0d41\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d7b","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"27","question":"\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d7d\u0d35\u0d7c \u0d2b\u0d3f\u0d37\u0d4d \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d2d\u0d3e\u0d17\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d09\u0d7e\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d41?","option1":"\u0d2e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d02","option2":"\u0d37\u0d21\u0d4d\u200c\u0d2a\u0d26\u0d02","option3":"\u0d09\u0d2d\u0d2f\u0d1c\u0d40\u0d35\u0d3f","option4":"\u0d09\u0d30\u0d17\u0d02","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"28","question":"\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d4b\u0d23\u0d3e\u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d05\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d3f?","option1":"\u0d12.\u0d0e\u0d02.\u0d28\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d7c","option2":"\u0d2a\u0d3f.\u0d1f\u0d3f. \u0d09\u0d37","option3":"\u0d37\u0d48\u0d28\u0d3f \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d7a","option4":"\u0d15\u0d46.\u0d2a\u0d3f. \u0d24\u0d4b\u0d2e\u0d38\u0d4d","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"29","question":"\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d15 \u0d28\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d47\u0d30 \u0d26\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d06\u0d1a\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d38\u0d46\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d02\u0d2c\u0d7c 16","option2":"\u0d38\u0d46\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d02\u0d2c\u0d7c 2","option3":"\u0d12\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4b\u0d2c\u0d7c 2","option4":"\u0d12\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4b\u0d2c\u0d7c 16","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"30","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d35\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d24 \u0d28\u0d4b\u0d2c\u0d7d \u0d38\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d1c\u0d47\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d4d","option1":"\u0d2a\u0d47\u0d7e\u0d2c\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d","option2":"\u0d17\u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d47\u0d32\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d7e","option3":"\u0d2e\u0d47\u0d30\u0d3f \u0d15\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d42\u0d31\u0d3f","option4":"\u0d1c\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7b \u0d06\u0d21\u0d02\u0d38\u0d4d ","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"31","question":"\u0d15\u0d4b\u0d7c\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d31\u0d47\u0d37\u0d7b \u0d15\u0d57\u0d7a\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d47\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41 \u0d35\u0d47\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d15\u0d41\u0d31\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1e \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d2a\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d27\u0d3f \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30?","option1":"25","option2":"18","option3":"21","option4":"35","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"32","question":"2013\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d40\u0d2f \u0d05\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d35\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d06\u0d30\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d21\u0d4b\u0d33\u0d3f \u0d05\u0d39\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d41\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d2f ","option2":" \u0d09\u0d37\u0d3e \u0d1c\u0d3e\u0d26\u0d35\u0d4d","option3":"\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d7b","option4":"\u0d2a\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d2f","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"33","question":"\u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d7b \u0d2d\u0d30\u0d23\u0d18\u0d1f\u0d28 \u0d2d\u0d47\u0d26\u0d17\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d05\u0d27\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d02 \u0d06\u0d7c\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d ?","option1":"\u0d38\u0d41\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40\u0d02\u0d15\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d24\u0d3f","option2":"\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d2a\u0d24\u0d3f","option3":"\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d2e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f","option4":"\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d32\u0d2e\u0d46\u0d7b\u0d31\u0d4d","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"34","question":"\u0d2c\u0d02\u0d17\u0d3e\u0d7e \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d2d\u0d1c\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d46\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d3f \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d30\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d4a\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"1905","option2":"1915","option3":"1904","option4":"1906","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"35","question":"\u0d09\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d30 \u0d31\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d\u0d35\u0d47\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d1c\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d42\u0d7c","option2":"\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d42\u0d21\u0d7d\u0d39\u0d3f","option3":"\u0d05\u0d32\u0d39\u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d26\u0d4d","option4":"\u0d1a\u0d46\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d48","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"36","question":"\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d34\u0d46 \u0d2a\u0d31\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d35\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d2a\u0d30\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37 \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d41\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d09\u0d7e\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d0e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d48\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d21\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d42\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f","option2":"\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d28\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d41\u0d24\u0d3f","option3":"\u0d15\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d02\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d41\u0d24\u0d3f","option4":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d41\u0d24\u0d3f","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"37","question":"\u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d36\u0d3e\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d24 \u0d2d\u0d42\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d41\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d35\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d35\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25 \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d17\u0d35\u0d7c\u0d23\u0d7c \u0d1c\u0d28\u0d31\u0d7d?","option1":"\u0d21\u0d7d\u0d39\u0d57\u0d38\u0d3f","option2":"\u0d35\u0d46\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d3f","option3":"\u0d15\u0d4b\u0d7a\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d","option4":"\u0d15\u0d34\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d7a \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d2d\u0d41","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"38","question":"\u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d7b \u0d2d\u0d30\u0d23\u0d18\u0d1f\u0d28 \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d7c\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d38\u0d2d\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d47\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d24\u0d46\u0d30\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1e\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f \u0d05\u0d02\u0d17\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d33\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d0e\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d23\u0d02?","option1":"292","option2":"285","option3":"385","option4":"395","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"39","question":"1953 \u0d7d \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d35\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d2a\u0d41\u0d28\u0d38\u0d02\u0d18\u0d1f\u0d28 \u0d15\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d40\u0d37\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d05\u0d02\u0d17\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d35\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d06\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d? ","option1":"\u0d38\u0d7c\u0d26\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d15\u0d46. \u0d0e\u0d02. \u0d2a\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d7c","option2":"\u0d38\u0d3f. \u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d17\u0d4b\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3f","option3":"\u0d39\u0d43\u0d26\u0d2f\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d25\u0d4d \u0d15\u0d41\u0d7a\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d41","option4":"\u0d1c\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d2b\u0d38\u0d7d \u0d05\u0d32\u0d3f","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"40","question":"\r\n\u0d0f\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d24\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d23\u0d35 \u0d35\u0d48\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d09\u0d7d\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d26\u0d28 \u0d15\u0d47\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d0e\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d46?","option1":"\u0d2e\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d4d","option2":"\u0d38\u0d42\u0d31\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d ","option3":"\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d4b\u0d02\u0d2c\u0d46","option4":"\u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d02\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d42\u0d7c","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"41","question":"\u0d2d\u0d30\u0d23\u0d18\u0d1f\u0d28\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 5 \u0d2e\u0d41\u0d24\u0d7d 11 \u0d35\u0d30\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d35\u0d15\u0d41\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d41\u0d15\u0d7e \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d46\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d4d \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d26\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d41?","option1":"\u0d2e\u0d57\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d36\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d7e","option2":"\u0d2a\u0d57\u0d30\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d41\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d4d","option3":"\u0d2e\u0d57\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d15 \u0d15\u0d1f\u0d2e\u0d15\u0d7e","option4":"\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d7c\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d15 \u0d24\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d7e","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"42","question":"\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d7c\u0d35\u0d4d \u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d13\u0d2b\u0d4d \u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d02\u0d2c\u0d48 ","option2":"\u0d21\u0d7d\u0d39\u0d3f ","option3":"\u0d1a\u0d46\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d48","option4":"\u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d02\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d42\u0d7c ","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"43","question":"\u0d17\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d39\u0d3f\u0d15 \u0d2a\u0d40\u0d21\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40\u0d15\u0d7e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d02\u0d30\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d23\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d7d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d02 \u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d35\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"2000","option2":"2002","option3":"2005","option4":"2010","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"44","question":"\u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d2d\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d38 \u0d15\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d40\u0d37\u0d7b\u0d31\u0d46 \ufffd\ufffd \u0d36\u0d41\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d36\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d \u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d you \u0d1c\u0d3f \u0d30\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d40\u0d15\u0d43\u0d24\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d32\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d23 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d2e\u0d3f \u0d2e\u0d41\u0d24\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d7c","option2":"\u0d21\u0d3f. \u0d0e\u0d38\u0d4d. \u0d15\u0d4b\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3f ","option3":"\u0d1c\u0d4b\u0d7a \u0d38\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d1c\u0d7b\u0d4d\u0d31 ","option4":"\u0d21\u0d4b. \u0d0e\u0d38\u0d4d. \u0d30\u0d3e\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d43\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d23\u0d7b","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"45","question":"\u0d38\u0d48\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d15 \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d32\u0d35\u0d4d \u0d35\u0d7c\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d46 \u0d35\u0d7c\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d3f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d46 \u0d24\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d46 \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d2a\u0d41\u0d32\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f \u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d38\u0d48\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d46 \ufffd\ufffd\u0d46 \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d7b \u0d15\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d4b\u0d33 \u0d2a\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d30\u0d23\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d41\u0d7d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d7b \u0d06\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d","option1":"\u0d07\u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d39\u0d3f\u0d02 \u0d32\u0d4b\u0d26\u0d3f","option2":"\u0d05\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d41\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d40\u0d7b \u0d16\u0d3f\u0d7d\u0d1c\u0d3f","option3":"\u0d39\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4b\u0d37\u0d3e \u0d24\u0d41\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d15\u0d4d ","option4":"\u0d15\u0d41\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d2c\u0d41\u0d26\u0d40\u0d7b \u0d10\u0d2c\u0d15\u0d4d ","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"46","question":"\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d40\u0d2a\u0d4d \u0d24\u0d41\u0d31\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d16\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02?","option1":"\u0d2a\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d2e \u0d2c\u0d02\u0d17\u0d3e\u0d7e","option2":"\u0d17\u0d41\u0d1c\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d","option3":"\u0d12\u0d31\u0d40\u0d38 ","option4":"\u0d06\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d4d\u0d30 \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d4d","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"47","question":"\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d3e \u0d32\u0d1c\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d2e\u0d30\u0d23\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d41 \u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d23\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d2f \u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d40\u0d37\u0d4d \u0d09\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d4b\u0d17\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d7b \u0d38\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d47\u0d34\u0d4d\u200c\u0d38\u0d28\u0d46 \u0d35\u0d15\u0d35\u0d30\u0d41\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d35\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3f?","option1":"\u0d2d\u0d17\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d02\u0d17\u0d4d","option2":"\u0d38\u0d41\u0d16\u0d4d \u0d26\u0d47\u0d35\u0d4d ","option3":"\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d4d \u0d17\u0d41\u0d30\u0d41","option4":"\u0d38\u0d42\u0d30\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d38\u0d46\u0d7b","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"48","question":"\u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \ufffd\ufffd\u0d46 \u0d2a\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1e\u0d3e\u0d31\u0d7b \u0d24\u0d40\u0d30 \u0d38\u0d2e\u0d24\u0d32\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d09\u0d7e\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":" \u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d24\u0d40\u0d30\u0d02","option2":"\u0d15\u0d4b\u0d31\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d7b\u0d21\u0d7d \u0d24\u0d40\u0d30\u0d02","option3":"\u0d17\u0d41\u0d1c\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d24\u0d40\u0d30\u0d02","option4":"\u0d15\u0d4a\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d7a \u0d24\u0d40\u0d30\u0d02","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"49","question":"\u0d06\u0d38\u0d42\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d23 \u0d15\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d40\u0d37\u0d7b\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d2f\u0d4b\u0d1c\u0d28 \u0d2d\u0d35\u0d7b","option2":"\u0d05\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d30\u0d40\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37 \u0d2d\u0d35\u0d7b","option3":" \u0d06\u0d28\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26 \u0d2d\u0d35\u0d7b","option4":"\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d7c\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d1a\u0d7b \u0d38\u0d26\u0d7b ","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"50","question":"\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d33\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d2f\u0d4b\u0d1c\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d38\u0d7c\u0d26\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d35\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d2d\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d4d \u0d2a\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d47\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d39\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d3f \u0d06\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d ?","option1":"\u0d15\u0d46. \u0d15\u0d47\u0d33\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7b ","option2":"\u0d35\u0d3f.\u0d2a\u0d3f. \u0d2e\u0d47\u0d28\u0d4b\u0d7b ","option3":"\u0d0e.\u0d15\u0d46. \u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33","option4":"\u0d1f\u0d3f.\u0d15\u0d46. \u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d27\u0d35\u0d7b ","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"51","question":"\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d35\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d36\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d02 \u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d35\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d1c\u0d40\u0d35\u0d28\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d2c\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d4d \u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d46\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30 \u0d2e\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d42\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d35\u0d30\u0d02 \u0d32\u0d2d\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d23\u0d02?","option1":"48 \u0d2e\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d42\u0d7c","option2":"24 \u0d2e\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d42\u0d7c","option3":"36 \u0d2e\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d42\u0d7c","option4":"12 \u0d2e\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d42\u0d7c","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"52","question":"\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2c\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d38 \u0d38\u0d30\u0d4b\u0d35\u0d7c \u0d24\u0d1f\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d15\u0d3f\u0d34\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d41\u0d19\u0d4d \u0d39\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d09\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2d\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d28\u0d26\u0d3f \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d28","option2":"\u0d17\u0d02\u0d17","option3":"\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d41","option4":"\u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d39\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d2a\u0d41\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"53","question":"\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d4d \u0d15\u0d4b\u0d7a\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d7b\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d05\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d02 \u0d06\u0d23\u0d46\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d16\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d38\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d47\u0d33\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d0e\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d35\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d2c\u0d4b\u0d02\u0d2c\u0d46","option2":"\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d39\u0d4b\u0d7c","option3":"\u0d2c\u0d02\u0d17\u0d3e\u0d7e","option4":"\u0d32\u0d15\u0d4d\u200c\u0d28\u0d57","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"54","question":"\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7b\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d0f\u0d15\u0d24, \u0d2a\u0d30\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d27\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d02, \u0d38\u0d41\u0d30\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37 \u0d07\u0d35\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d46\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d48\u0d2c\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d47\u0d24\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d33\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d42\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d35\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d28\u0d02?","option1":"\u0d38\u0d48\u0d2c\u0d7c \u0d1f\u0d46\u0d31\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d02","option2":"\u0d2b\u0d3f\u0d37\u0d3f\u0d02\u0d17\u0d4d","option3":"\u0d38\u0d48\u0d2c\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d4d\u200c\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d19\u0d4d","option4":"\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d19\u0d4d","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"55","question":"\u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7b\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d2e\u0d27\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d24\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d \u0d24\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d46\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d \u0d15\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d12\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d41\u0d35\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d05\u0d2e\u0d47\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15","option2":"\u0d38\u0d4b\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d \u0d2f\u0d42\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d7b","option3":"\u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d7b","option4":"\u0d1c\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d7b","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"56","question":"1959 \u0d7d \u0d1c\u0d7c\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d3e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d47\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d15 \u0d38\u0d39\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d07\u0d30\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d41\u0d30\u0d41\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d36\u0d3e\u0d32 \u0d0e\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d31\u0d42\u0d7c\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d32","option2":"\u0d2c\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d4d","option3":"\u0d1c\u0d02\u0d37\u0d21\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d42\u0d7c","option4":"\u0d26\u0d41\u0d7c\u0d17\u0d3e\u0d2a\u0d42\u0d7c","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"57","question":"\u0d15\u0d47\u0d30\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d2a\u0d46\u0d30\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d1f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d30\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d15\u0d4a\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3f","option2":"\u0d15\u0d4b\u0d34\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d4d ","option3":"\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d7d ","option4":"\u0d35\u0d47\u0d23\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"58","question":"1930 \u0d32\u0d46 \u0d09\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d41\u0d38\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d39\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d28 \u0d35\u0d47\u0d26\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d2f \u0d15\u0d47\u0d30\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d32\u0d02?","option1":"\u0d35\u0d1f\u0d15\u0d30 ","option2":"\u0d15\u0d4a\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f","option3":"\u0d2a\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d42\u0d7c","option4":"\u0d06\u0d32\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d42\u0d7c","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"59","question":"\u0d15\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d06\u0d30\u0d02\u0d2d\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d24\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33\u0d3f \u0d38\u0d4d\u200c\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d7d\u0d35\u0d47\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d2a\u0d23\u0d3f \u0d2a\u0d42\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d? ","option1":"1961","option2":"1955","option3":"1959","option4":"1965","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"60","question":"\u0d39\u0d4b\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d42\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d17\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d02 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d24\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d2d\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d21\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d4d","option2":"\u0d2b\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d4d","option3":"\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d7b","option4":"\u0d2a\u0d4b\u0d7c\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d41\u0d17\u0d40\u0d38\u0d4d","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"61","question":"\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d34\u0d46\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d31\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d35\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d41 \u0d15\u0d43\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d41\u0d17\u0d24\u0d15\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d15\u0d47\u0d30\u0d33 \u0d38\u0d3e\u0d39\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d05\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d26\u0d2e\u0d3f \u0d05\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d32\u0d2d\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d34","option2":"\u0d05\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d32\u0d2e\u0d23\u0d3f ","option3":"\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d3e \u0d2a\u0d42\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d7e","option4":"\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d02 \u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d35\u0d39\u0d43\u0d26\u0d2f\u0d02","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"62","question":"\u0d05\u0d28\u0d41\u0d15\u0d7b \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d2a\u0d26\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7b\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d05\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d ?","option1":"\u0d05\u0d33\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d7b","option2":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d15\u0d7b","option3":"\u0d05\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1b\u0d7b","option4":"\u0d2c\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d41 ","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"63","question":"\u0d24\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30 \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d27\u0d02?","option1":"3","option2":"2","option3":"4","option4":"5","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"64","question":"\u0d28\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d06\u0d30\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d24\u0d42\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d2e\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d?","option1":" \u0d2a\u0d3f.\u0d38\u0d3f. \u0d15\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d43\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d23\u0d7b","option2":"\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d41\u0d35\u0d7c\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f \r\n","option3":"\u0d2a\u0d3f.\u0d38\u0d3f. \u0d17\u0d4b\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d7b","option4":"\u0d0e.\u0d15\u0d46. \u0d17\u0d4b\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d7b","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"65","question":"\u0d15\u0d4b\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d41\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d7b \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d36\u0d48\u0d32\u0d3f \u0d15\u0d4a\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d \u0d05\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d46\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d2d\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d46 \u0d35\u0d46\u0d31\u0d41\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d35\u0d7b","option2":"\u0d2d\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d46 \u0d2e\u0d31\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d2d\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d4d ","option3":"\u0d2d\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d35\u0d30\u0d41\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d7d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d2d\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d4d ","option4":"\u0d2d\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d41\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d02 \u0d2a\u0d31\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d2d\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d4d","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"66","question":"\u0d35\u0d46\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7b \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d41 \u0d15\u0d43\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d ?","option1":"\u0d13\u0d1f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d4d","option2":"\u0d15\u0d1f\u0d7d \u0d24\u0d40\u0d30\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d","option3":"\u0d05\u0d38\u0d41\u0d30\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d ","option4":"\u0d0f\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d7e","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"67","question":"'Where there is life there is hope' \u0d08 \u0d35\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d0f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d09\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f \u0d24\u0d7c\u0d1c\u0d4d\u0d1c\u0d2e \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d1c\u0d40\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d24\u0d40\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d15\u0d7e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32 ","option2":"\u0d1c\u0d40\u0d35\u0d28\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4b\u0d33\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d02 \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d24\u0d40\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d35\u0d15\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d ","option3":"\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d24\u0d40\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d15\u0d7e \u0d07\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d \u0d1c\u0d40\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d02","option4":"\u0d1c\u0d40\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d24\u0d40\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d15\u0d7e \u0d15\u0d41\u0d31\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d24\u0d3f","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"68","question":"\u0d09\u0d2a\u0d2e\u0d3e \u0d24\u0d7d\u0d2a\u0d41\u0d30\u0d41\u0d37\u0d7b \u0d38\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d09\u0d26\u0d3e\u0d39\u0d30\u0d23\u0d02 \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d38\u0d41\u0d16\u0d26\u0d41\u0d03\u0d16\u0d02 ","option2":"\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d16\u0d15\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d02","option3":"\u0d24\u0d33\u0d3f\u0d7c\u0d2e\u0d47\u0d28\u0d3f","option4":"\u0d28\u0d40\u0d32\u0d2e\u0d47\u0d18\u0d02","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"69","question":"'John prefers English novels to Malayalam ones' \u0d08 \u0d35\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33 \u0d24\u0d7c\u0d1c\u0d4d\u0d1c\u0d2e \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d1c\u0d4b\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d4b\u0d35\u0d32\u0d41\u0d15\u0d33\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d07\u0d02\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d40\u0d37\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d4b\u0d35\u0d32\u0d41\u0d15\u0d33\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d07\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d","option2":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d4b\u0d35\u0d32\u0d41\u0d15\u0d33\u0d47\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d7e \u0d07\u0d02\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d40\u0d37\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d4b\u0d35\u0d32\u0d41\u0d15\u0d33\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d \u0d1c\u0d4b\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d02","option3":"\u0d1c\u0d4b\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d4b\u0d35\u0d32\u0d41\u0d15\u0d33\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d07\u0d02\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d40\u0d37\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d4b\u0d35\u0d32\u0d41\u0d15\u0d33\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d07\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d ","option4":"\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d07\u0d02\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d40\u0d37\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d4b\u0d35\u0d32\u0d41\u0d15\u0d7e \u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d \u0d1c\u0d4b\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d02","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"70","question":"\u0d2e\u0d28\u0d4b\u0d39\u0d30\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d33\u0d3e\u0d2f \u0d15\u0d3e\u0d34\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d15\u0d7e \u0d05\u0d35\u0d7b \u0d05\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d41. \u0d08 \u0d35\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d24\u0d46\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d2f \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d2f\u0d4b\u0d17\u0d02 \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d34\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d15\u0d7e","option2":"\u0d05\u0d35\u0d7b","option3":"\u0d2e\u0d28\u0d4b\u0d39\u0d30\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d33\u0d3e\u0d2f ","option4":"\u0d05\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d41","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"71","question":"Mr. Manoj ........... the work in November last year","option1":"Start","option2":"Started","option3":"will start","option4":"have started","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"72","question":"Find the exact word which means that happens now and then","option1":"occasional","option2":"frequent","option3":"often","option4":"gradual","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"73","question":"An article is wrongly used here. Find the word:","option1":"a flower","option2":"an African","option3":"a furniture","option4":"the ganges","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"74","question":"His actions are","option1":"destroyer","option2":"destruction","option3":"destructive","option4":"destroyed","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"75","question":"He is jealous...... his friend's success","option1":"with","option2":"on","option3":"of","option4":"by","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"76","question":"They went to a film,..........","option1":"did they?","option2":"didn't they?","option3":"do they?","option4":"haven't they?","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"77","question":"When I reached the station, the train:","option1":"had left","option2":"have left","option3":"left","option4":"will leave","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"78","question":"Antonym of 'accept'","option1":"refuse","option2":"rebuke","option3":"receive","option4":"reject","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"79","question":"Synonym of 'Cautious'","option1":"beware","option2":"careful","option3":"casual","option4":"calm","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"80","question":"Plural of 'Knife'","option1":"Knives","option2":"Knifes","option3":"Knifs","option4":"Knivfes","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"81","question":"Which is the .......... city in India?","option1":"big","option2":"biggest","option3":"bigger","option4":"most biggest","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"82","question":"John and his brother ............ hard","option1":"working","option2":"will be work","option3":"work","option4":"works","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"83","question":"All the milk ............sour","option1":"was","option2":"were","option3":"are","option4":"has","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"84","question":"Add a prefix to get the opposite meaning of the word 'able'","option1":"disable","option2":"inable","option3":"unable","option4":"misable","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"85","question":"The word 'martial' means","option1":"of marriage","option2":"relating to war","option3":"upholding law","option4":"rule or docrine","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"86","question":"Plural of 'manservant'","option1":"manservants","option2":"menservants","option3":"menservant","option4":"mensservants","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"87","question":"Select an uncountable noun from the following:","option1":"pin","option2":"poem","option3":"train","option4":"poetry","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"88","question":"Which of the following words are wrongly paired?","option1":"Hunter-Huntress","option2":"Bridegroom-Bride","option3":"Sultan-Sultana","option4":"Bull-Belly","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"89","question":"Thieves broke into her house here the phrase broke intomeans","option1":"begin suddenly ","option2":"enter by force","option3":"collapse","option4":"split into parts","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"90","question":"Panorama has the meaning","option1":"wild and noisy disorder","option2":"wide sight without interruption","option3":"whatever happens by chance","option4":"what cannot be understood","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"91","question":"\u0d06\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d30 \u0d15\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d7c\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d2c\u0d7c","option2":"\u0d1c\u0d39\u0d3e\u0d02\u0d17\u0d40\u0d7c","option3":"\u0d05\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d2c\u0d7c","option4":"\u0d14\u0d31\u0d02\u0d17\u0d38\u0d40\u0d2c\u0d4d","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"92","question":"\u0d2a\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1e\u0d3e\u0d31\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4a\u0d34\u0d41\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d0f\u0d15 \u0d39\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d7b \u0d28\u0d26\u0d3f \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d05\u0d33\u0d15\u0d28\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26","option2":"\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d41","option3":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d47\u0d30\u0d3f ","option4":"\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d28","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"93","question":"\u0d15\u0d47\u0d30\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d35\u0d28\u0d02\u0d35\u0d15\u0d41\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d7b\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d24\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d41? ","option1":"\u0d35\u0d34\u0d41\u0d24\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d ","option2":"\u0d35\u0d2f\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d","option3":"\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d","option4":"\u0d07\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f ","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"94","question":"\u0d35\u0d48\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d7b \u0d2c\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d41\u0d31\u0d35\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d42\u0d32\u0d02 \u0d09\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d30\u0d4b\u0d17\u0d02 \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d2c\u0d46\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d2c\u0d46\u0d31\u0d3f","option2":"\u0d17\u0d4b\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d7c","option3":" \u0d15\u0d23","option4":"\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d02","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"95","question":"\u0d15\u0d47\u0d30\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d32\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d38\u0d2d\u0d3e \u0d2e\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d21\u0d32\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d33\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d0e\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d23\u0d02?","option1":"14","option2":"28","option3":"20","option4":"25","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"96","question":"\u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d17\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d39\u0d3f\u0d15 \u0d2a\u0d40\u0d21\u0d28 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d30\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d23 \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d35\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d46\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d4d ?","option1":"2005","option2":"2004","option3":"2006","option4":"2000","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"97","question":"\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d34\u0d46 \u0d2a\u0d31\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d35\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d \u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d40\u0d2f \u0d2b\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d02 \u0d05\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d2e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d33 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2e?","option1":"\u0d1c\u0d40\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d28\u0d57\u0d15","option2":"\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d47\u0d39\u0d38\u0d40\u0d2e \r\n","option3":"\u0d24\u0d41\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d2d\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d02","option4":"\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d7c\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d02","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"98","question":"\u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d0f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d2a\u0d34\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d02\u0d1a\u0d46\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d2a\u0d7c\u0d35\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d24\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d30?\r\n","option1":"\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d4d\u0d2f","option2":"\u0d06\u0d30\u0d35\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d3f ","option3":"\u0d2a\u0d42\u0d7c\u0d35\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d18\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d02","option4":"\u0d2a\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d18\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d02","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"99","question":"\u0d38\u0d48\u0d32\u0d7b\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d \u0d35\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d3f \u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d40\u0d2f\u0d4b\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d1c\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d41? ","option1":"\u0d07\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f","option2":"\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d","option3":"\u0d35\u0d2f\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d","option4":"\u0d24\u0d43\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d36\u0d42\u0d7c","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"100","question":"\u0d17\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d3f\u0d1c\u0d3f \u0d2a\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d38\u0d2e\u0d30 \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d ?","option1":"\u0d16\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d2b\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02","option2":"\u0d09\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d41\u0d38\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d39\u0d02","option3":"\u0d2c\u0d02\u0d17\u0d3e\u0d7e \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d2d\u0d1c\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d46\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d46 \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d38\u0d2e\u0d30\u0d02","option4":"\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d \u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02","answer":"3"}],"question_paper2":[{"question_no":"1","question":"Name the District where most number of Railway Stations in Kerala?","option1":"Ernakulam","option2":"Palakkad","option3":"Trissur","option4":"Thiruvananthapuram","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"2","question":"In which district is 'Ponmudi Dam' situated","option1":"Alapuzha","option2":"Idukki","option3":"Pathanamthitta","option4":"Kollam","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"3","question":"Which Road is the first Rubberised Road in Kerala?","option1":"Kottayam - Kumali","option2":"Kottayam-Erumelly","option3":"Thiruvananthapuram-Kanyakumari","option4":"Edappally-Palakkad","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"4","question":"The first floating ATM in India is established by SBT at:","option1":"Kochi","option2":"Alapuzha","option3":"Quilon","option4":"Thiruvananthapuram","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"5","question":"Which prime minister inaugurated 'Silent Valley' National Park?","option1":"Rajeev Gandhi","option2":"Indira Gandhi","option3":"V.P.Singh","option4":"Jawaharlal Nehru","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"6","question":"How many Time Zones are in India?","option1":"One","option2":"Two","option3":"Three","option4":"None of these","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"7","question":"Which names below is not related to river 'Kavery'?","option1":"Andhra Ganga","option2":"Telugu Ganga","option3":"Dheshini Ganga","option4":"The Ganga","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"8","question":"_______ commonly known as 'October heat':","option1":"North-East Monsoon","option2":"North-West Monsoon","option3":"East-West Monsoon","option4":"Cyclones","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"9","question":"The Red colour of red soil due to the presence of:","option1":"Potassium Permanganate","option2":"Iron Oxide","option3":"Iron sulphide","option4":"Magnesium Sulphate","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"10","question":"Corbet National Park is situated in which state?","option1":"Madhya Pradesh","option2":"Orissa","option3":"Uttarakhand","option4":"Jharkhand","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"11","question":"The Book 'The First War of Independence' was written by:","option1":"Mangal Pandey","option2":"V.D.Sarvaker","option3":"S.N.Sen","option4":"Nirud C Chaudari","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"12","question":"Who is known as Father of Indian Economy and Indian Politics?","option1":"Gopala Krishna Gokhale","option2":"Dada Bai Navaroji","option3":"Lal Lajapath Rai","option4":"Swami Vivekananda","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"13","question":"Jalian Valabagh Massacre was took place on:","option1":"13th April 1913","option2":"13th May 1913","option3":"13th April 1914","option4":"13th May 1914","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"14","question":"Head Quarters of National Investment on Ayog (NIA)","option1":"Kochi","option2":"Bangalore","option3":"Mumbai","option4":"New Delhi","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"15","question":"The motto of SPG (Special Protection Group):","option1":"Bravery Dedication Security","option2":"Truth wins","option3":"Sathyameva Jayathe","option4":"Security at always development","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"16","question":"cover Page of Indian Constitution was designed by:","option1":"Navindra Nath Tagore","option2":"Nandalal Bose","option3":"Nandal Gholh","option4":"B.N.Rao","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"17","question":"The first Democracy in the world:","option1":"India","option2":"Greece","option3":"Britian","option4":"Switzerland","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"18","question":"Who is known as 'Modern Budha'?","option1":"Sardar K.M.Panikar","option2":"Sardar Vallabhai Pattel","option3":"Dr. B.R.Ambedkar","option4":"Sree Sakaracharya","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"19","question":"The first acting President of India:","option1":"V.V.Giri","option2":"B.P.Jetty","option3":"Dr.S.Radhakrishnan","option4":"K.R.Narayanan","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"20","question":"University Grand Commission (UGC) started during ______ Five Year Plan","option1":"First","option2":"Second","option3":"Third","option4":"Fourth","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"21","question":"The first chairman of National Human Right Commission:","option1":"Justice K.G.Balakrishnan","option2":"Justice Rahmath Mishra","option3":"Justice J.K.Kushi","option4":"Justice Krian Joseph","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"22","question":"Which country passed the rights to information Act first?","option1":"Switzerland","option2":"China","option3":"Sweeden","option4":"India","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"23","question":"International Woman's day is on:","option1":"March 8","option2":"September 5","option3":"December 1","option4":"May 8","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"24","question":"Dowry prohibited Act was passed by the Parliament in:","option1":"1961","option2":"1965","option3":"1962","option4":"1951","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"25","question":"The first Vigilance Commissioner of India:","option1":"N.Srinivas Rao","option2":"B.Srinivass Iyyar","option3":"R.N.Prasad","option4":"Jullier Muhammed Sadir Ali","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"26","question":"2014 Common Wealth game held in:","option1":"Glasgow","option2":"Inchion","option3":"Brazil","option4":"India","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"27","question":"Father of Malayalam film:","option1":"Adoor Gopalakrishnan","option2":"J.C.Daniel","option3":"M.T. Vasudevan Nair","option4":"Prem Nazir","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"28","question":"Who is known of 'Kerala Scott'?","option1":"C.V. Raman Pillai","option2":"K. Kelappan","option3":"G. Sankarakurup","option4":"S.K. Pottakkad","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"29","question":"Who said \"Knowledge is power and Ignorance is death\"?","option1":"Fracis Bacon","option2":"Swami Vivekananda","option3":"Budha","option4":"Aristotle","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"30","question":"Who wrote the famous book'The Path of Power'?","option1":"Dr.Annie Besant","option2":"Margrat Thatcher","option3":"Indira Gandhi","option4":"Benazir bhutto","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"31","question":"Long walk to Freedom is an Autobiography of:","option1":"Mahatma Gandhi","option2":"Nelson Mandela","option3":"Martin Luther King","option4":"Adolf Hitler","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"32","question":"Boz is the pet name of:","option1":"Charles Dickens","option2":"George Bernard Shaw","option3":"Shakespeare","option4":"Jawaharlal Nehru","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"33","question":"Zulu's are tribal people lives in:","option1":"India","option2":"South America","option3":"South Africa","option4":"Astralia","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"34","question":"oneirology is the study of:","option1":"Birds","option2":"Insects","option3":"Dreams","option4":"Propnorms","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"35","question":"Which among the following is not an isotope of Hydrogen?","option1":"Protium","option2":"Deuterium","option3":"Tritium","option4":"Curium","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"36","question":"Number of groups in the modern periodic table:","option1":"18","option2":"16","option3":"7","option4":"13","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"37","question":"Most abundant metal in the human body?","option1":"Nitrogen","option2":"Calcium","option3":"Phosphorus","option4":"Iron","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"38","question":"Yellow colour of turmeric is due to:","option1":"Carotene","option2":"Curcumine","option3":"Chlorophyll","option4":"Xanthophyll","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"39","question":"The chemical name of vitamin E:","option1":"Tocopherol","option2":"Phylloofuinone","option3":"Calciferol","option4":"Retinol","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"40","question":"The substance which are used for artificial raining:","option1":"Silver Bromide","option2":"Silver Iodine","option3":"Silver Nitrate","option4":"Sodium Chloride","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"41","question":"Animal having heaviest liver but lightest heart:","option1":"Elephant","option2":"Cow","option3":"Pig","option4":"Rabbit","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"42","question":"Normal blood cholesterol level of human body:","option1":"80-120 mg\/100 ml","option2":"150-260 mg\/100 ml","option3":"100-180 mg\/100 ml","option4":"150-150 mg\/100 ml","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"43","question":"In which part of the human body is Ricket Effects?","option1":"Eyes","option2":"Born","option3":"Muscles","option4":"Immune system","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"44","question":"Father of Indian Railway is:","option1":"Lord Dalhousie","option2":"Lord Rippon","option3":"Lord Wellesley","option4":"Lord Curzon","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"45","question":"As mosquito is to Riggler cockroach is to:","option1":"Maggol","option2":"Cater Piller","option3":"Nymph","option4":"Chitin","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"46","question":"Name the bird, which can fly backwards:","option1":"Duck","option2":"Ostrich","option3":"Kiwi","option4":"Humming Bird","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"47","question":"Father of Green Revolution:","option1":"Norman Borlaug","option2":"Dr. M.S.Swaminathan","option3":"William Gaud","option4":"Varghese Kurian","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"48","question":"Unfinished Dream is a book written by:","option1":"M.S. Swaminathan","option2":"Varghese Kurian","option3":"Salim Ali","option4":"Sachin Tendulkar","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"49","question":"Leading producers of milk in India is:","option1":"Kerala","option2":"Rajasthan","option3":"Andra Pradesh","option4":"Gujarat","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"50","question":"First malayalee Woman to appear in Indian Postage Stamp:","option1":"P.T.Usha","option2":"Alphonsamma","option3":"Annie Besent","option4":"Dr. Arunthathi Roy","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"51","question":"World Telecommunication day is observed on:","option1":"October 9","option2":"May 17","option3":"May 7","option4":"June 5","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"52","question":"Which part of the Indian constitution is called magnacarta of India or key stone of the constitution?","option1":"Part III","option2":"Preamble","option3":"Article 19","option4":"Article 24","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"53","question":"Father of Indian Planning is:","option1":"M.N.Roy","option2":"Narayanan Agarwal","option3":"Amarthya Sen","option4":"M.Viswaswarayya","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"54","question":"Hypermetropia means:","option1":"Short sightness","option2":"Long sightness","option3":"Astigmatism","option4":"Night Blindness","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"55","question":"The Keralite whose Birth day and Death anniversary are celebrated as holiday by Kerala Government:","option1":"Sri.Narayana Gru","option2":"Sir KRISHNA","option3":"sREE sankaran","option4":"Ayyankali","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"56","question":"Who was the founder of Nair Service Society(NSS)?","option1":"Veluppilly Naolesan","option2":"Sri.Narayana Guru","option3":"Mannath Padmanabhan","option4":"Kannan Nair","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"57","question":"Who was the First General Secretary of SNDP?","option1":"Sri.Narayana Guru","option2":"Kumaranasan","option3":"V.T.Bhattathirippad","option4":"K.Kelappan","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"58","question":"A.K.G Statue is situated at:","option1":"Kannur","option2":"Thiruvananthapuram","option3":"New Delhi","option4":"Payyannur","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"59","question":"Malabar Economic Union was founded by:","option1":"Dr. Palpu","option2":"Kesavan","option3":"C.V.Raman Pillai","option4":"Panikkar","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"60","question":"Father of cloning:","option1":"Ian Wilmutt","option2":"Griger Mendel","option3":"Watson","option4":"Har Govind Khorana","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"61","question":"In a democracy every one ______ obey the laws of the country.","option1":"can","option2":"will","option3":"may","option4":"ought to","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"62","question":"Mr. Gupta accompanied by his two sons, ______ going on a tour abroad.","option1":"are","option2":"has","option3":"is","option4":"were","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"63","question":"______ furniture arrived for you this morning.","option1":"the","option2":"a","option3":"an","option4":"some","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"64","question":"What is paper made?","option1":"of","option2":"with","option3":"on","option4":"upon","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"65","question":"When I left the house, I _____ all the rooms.","option1":"locked","option2":"had locked","option3":"has locked","option4":"have locked","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"66","question":"He said,\"I shall come\"- this can be rewrite into indirect speech as:","option1":"He said that he shall come","option2":"He said that he might come","option3":"He said that he would come","option4":"He said that he should come","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"67","question":"Arrange into proper sentence:\r\nan old man, saw, I, crossing the road","option1":"An old man crossing the road, I saw","option2":"I saw an old man, crossing the road","option3":"I crossing the road, saw an old man","option4":"An old man saw, I crossing the road","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"68","question":"Honesty is a virtue. It is an exceedingly wise policy:","option1":"too","option2":"next","option3":"but","option4":"equally","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"69","question":"He left the room open, the underline word here is:","option1":"an adjective","option2":"an adverb","option3":"a noun","option4":"a verb","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"70","question":"If I had a million pounds.","option1":"I had bought an estate","option2":"I will by an estate","option3":"I would buy an estate","option4":"I would have bought an estate","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"71","question":"The car ______ at the gate of the house.","option1":"looked out","option2":"pulled up","option3":"set in","option4":"gave in","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"72","question":"An ignorant person, especially one pretending to have knowledge is called:","option1":"iconoclast","option2":"ignoramus","option3":"inebitrate","option4":"misogamist","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"73","question":"I _______ my favorite book.","option1":"reread","option2":"overread","option3":"preread","option4":"antiread","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"74","question":"The antonym of 'dismis' is","option1":"discharge","option2":"disprove","option3":"repeal","option4":"reinstate","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"75","question":"The toy was very attractive, but nobody knew its mode of operation, the substitute for the underlined words is:","option1":"locus standi","option2":"in tato","option3":"modus operandi","option4":"pro tempore","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"76","question":"The passenger had an ______ with the ticket examiner for 10 minites.","option1":"Alternative","option2":"alternate","option3":"alternation","option4":"altercation","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"77","question":"The plural of rhinoceros is:","option1":"rhinoceroses","option2":"rhinoceros","option3":"rhinocerosis","option4":"rhinocerosess","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"78","question":"Pick out the correct spelling:","option1":"Memorandem","option2":"memorendem","option3":"memorandum","option4":"memorendam","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"79","question":"My grand father usually had forty winks after lunch the underlined words mean:","option1":"a short walk","option2":"a short sleep","option3":"read for a while","option4":"a short talk","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"80","question":"The word 'Fradulence' means:","option1":"Congregation","option2":"custom","option3":"correction","option4":"corruption","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"81","question":"1\/2+1\/3+ ____ =1","option1":"5\/6","option2":"1\/6","option3":"2\/3","option4":"1\/3","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"82","question":"Articles are brought for Rs.400 and sold for Rs.560. Find the profit percentage?","option1":"45","option2":"60","option3":"40","option4":"65","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"83","question":"The difference between simple interest and compound interest on Rs.2500 for 2 years at 6% per annum is:","option1":"Rs.9","option2":"Rs.90","option3":"Rs.2509","option4":"Rs.191","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"84","question":"If A:B = 7:9 and B:C = 3:5 then A:B:c is =","option1":"7:9:5","option2":"21:35:45","option3":"7:9:15","option4":"7:3:15","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"85","question":"A train 150m long running at a speed of 60km\/hour takes 30 seconds to cross a bridge. What is the length of the bridge?","option1":"200m","option2":"500m","option3":"3.5km","option4":"350m","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"86","question":"A can do a piece of work in 6 days and B in 12 days. If they work together, in how many days will they finish the work?","option1":"4 days","option2":"5 days","option3":"12 days","option4":"10 days","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"87","question":"The mean of 50 values is 15.What will be the new mean if each value is multiplied by 2?","option1":"15","option2":"30","option3":"50","option4":"100","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"88","question":"A wire in the form of a circle of radius 84cm is cut and bent in the form of a square. If \u312b is taken as 22\/7, the side of the square (in cm) is:","option1":"88","option2":"110","option3":"132","option4":"None of these","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"89","question":"Find the next number in the series: \r\n3,4,8,17,33, ____","option1":"63","option2":"65","option3":"66","option4":"58","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"90","question":"Paper is to Pen as garden is to:","option1":"apade","option2":"lawn","option3":"flowers","option4":"health","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"91","question":"If + means x, - means \u00f7 , x means -, and \u00f7 means +, then 9+8\u00f78-4x9=:","option1":"26","option2":"17","option3":"65","option4":"11","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"92","question":"Which of the following will come next?\r\nBHL, DJN, FLP, _____","option1":"HNR","option2":"HOS","option3":"IOS","option4":"INR","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"93","question":"Find the odd one out:","option1":"Veena","option2":"Flute","option3":"Violin","option4":"Sitar","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"94","question":"If TEACH is coded as XIEGL, STUDY will be coded as:","option1":"WXYHC","option2":"WXZID","option3":"WXYHV","option4":"WXVHC","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"95","question":"Pointing to a man, a woman said,\"His mother is the only daughter of my mother\". How is the woman related to the man?","option1":"Daughter","option2":"Mother","option3":"Sister","option4":"Grandmother","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"96","question":"Manu walks 5km towards North, then turns to his left and walks 4km. He again turns left and walks for 5km. At this point he turns to his left and walks for 5km. How many km is he from the sarting poin","option1":"5 km","option2":"2 km","option3":"3 km","option4":"1 km","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"97","question":"What is the correct time when the mirror image of the clock reads 7.15?","option1":"9.20","option2":"2.35","option3":"4.45","option4":"9.25","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"98","question":"How many 8's are there in the following sequence which are preceded by 5 but not immediately followed by 3?\n58375863854584765583587558285","option1":"8","option2":"5","option3":"7","option4":"4","answer":"4"}],"question_paper3":[{"question_no":"1","question":"\u0d0f\u0d24\u0d41 \u0d28\u0d26\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d1c\u0d32\u0d38\u0d47\u0d1a\u0d28 \u0d2a\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d7c\u0d26\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d30\u0d4b\u0d35\u0d7c?","option1":"\u0d2e\u0d39\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d26\u0d3f","option2":"\u0d28\u0d7c\u0d2e\u0d26 ","option3":"\u0d15\u0d43\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d23 ","option4":"\u0d17\u0d4b\u0d26\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d30\u0d3f ","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"2","question":"\u0d13\u0d7e \u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d2e\u0d32\u0d47\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d07\u0d7b\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d42\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d ?","option1":"\u0d15\u0d4a\u0d7d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24","option2":"\u0d2d\u0d4b\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d7d ","option3":"\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d42\u0d21\u0d7d\u0d39\u0d3f ","option4":"\u0d39\u0d48\u0d26\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d26\u0d4d ","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"3","question":"\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d41\u0d28\u0d26\u0d40\u0d24\u0d1f \u0d38\u0d02\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7b\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d2d\u0d3e\u0d17\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f \u0d39\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a \u0d15\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d46\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d ?","option1":"\u0d1c\u0d4b\u0d7a \u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d37\u0d7d ","option2":"\u0d06\u0d7c.\u0d21\u0d3f.\u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d7c\u0d1c\u0d3f ","option3":"\u0d05\u0d32\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d7c \u0d15\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d02\u0d39\u0d3e\u0d02","option4":"\u0d26\u0d2f\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d3e\u0d39\u0d4d\u200c\u0d28\u0d3f ","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"4","question":"\u0d2e\u0d28\u0d41\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d43\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d07\u0d02\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d40\u0d37\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d47\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d24\u0d7c\u0d1c\u0d2e \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d2e\u0d36\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f ","option2":"\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d02 \u0d1c\u0d4b\u0d7a\u0d38\u0d4d","option3":"\u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d7e\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d7d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7b\u0d38\u0d4d ","option4":"\u0d21\u0d4b. \u0d2e\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d7d ","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"5","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d1c\u0d48\u0d28\u0d2e\u0d24 \u0d38\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d47\u0d33\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d46\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d46?\r\n","option1":"\u0d35\u0d48\u0d36\u0d3e\u0d16\u0d3f ","option2":"\u0d35\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d2d\u0d3f ","option3":"\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d32\u0d40\u0d2a\u0d41\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 ","option4":"\u0d2a\u0d35\u0d2a\u0d41\u0d30\u0d3f ","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"6","question":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d37\u0d3f\u0d15 \u0d2a\u0d41\u0d30\u0d4b\u0d17\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d35\u0d47\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f \u0d1c\u0d32\u0d38\u0d47\u0d1a\u0d28 \u0d2a\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d7e \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d24\u0d41\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d2d\u0d30\u0d23\u0d3e\u0d27\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3f? ","option1":"\u0d17\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d41\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d40\u0d7b \u0d24\u0d41\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d ","option2":"\u0d2b\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4b\u0d37\u0d3e \u0d24\u0d41\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d ","option3":"\u0d1c\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d41\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d40\u0d7b \u0d24\u0d41\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d ","option4":"\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d39\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d26\u0d4d \u0d2c\u0d3f\u0d7b \u0d24\u0d41\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d ","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"7","question":"\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d17\u0d7e \u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d35\u0d02\u0d36\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d35\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d35\u0d7c\u0d37\u0d02?","option1":"1520","option2":"1526","option3":"1536","option4":"1556","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"8","question":"1857 \u0d32\u0d46 \u0d2e\u0d39\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d2f \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d35\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d47\u0d24\u0d43\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d7d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d2e\u0d41\u0d15\u0d7e \u0d1a\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d35\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f ? ","option1":"\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d4d \u0d09\u0d26\u0d4d \u0d27\u0d57\u0d33","option2":"\u0d2c\u0d39\u0d26\u0d42\u0d7c\u0d37 I","option3":"\u0d2c\u0d39\u0d26\u0d42\u0d7c\u0d37 I I ","option4":"\u0d05\u0d39\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d26\u0d4d \u0d37\u0d3e ","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"9","question":"\u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d0f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d05\u0d35\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d7b\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d26\u0d47\u0d36 \u0d36\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f? ","option1":"\u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d7b ","option2":"\u0d21\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d4d","option3":"\u0d2b\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d7b\u0d38\u0d4d","option4":"\u0d2a\u0d4b\u0d7c\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d41\u0d17\u0d40\u0d38\u0d4d","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"10","question":"\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d28\u0d3e \u0d38\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d1c \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d2a\u0d15\u0d7b ? ","option1":"\u0d15\u0d47\u0d36\u0d35 \u0d1a\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d30 \u0d38\u0d46\u0d7b ","option2":"\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d3e\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d02 \u0d2e\u0d4b\u0d39\u0d7b \u0d31\u0d4b\u0d2f\u0d4d \r\n","option3":"\u0d06\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d02 \u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d21\u0d41\u0d30\u0d02\u0d17\u0d4d \r\n","option4":"\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d2e\u0d3f \u0d26\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26 \u0d38\u0d30\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d24\u0d3f ","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"11","question":"\u0d2d\u0d30\u0d23\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d09\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d4b\u0d17\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25 \u0d24\u0d32\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d30\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40\u0d2f \u0d24\u0d32\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d05\u0d34\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d24\u0d1f\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d30\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d7d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d40\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d3f:","option1":"\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d4d\u200c\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d7d \r\n","option2":"\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d24 \r\n","option3":"\u0d38\u0d46\u0d7b\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d7d \u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d1c\u0d7b\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d31\u0d4b \r\n","option4":"\u0d07\u0d35\u0d2f\u0d4a\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32 ","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"12","question":"2017 \u0d32\u0d46 \u0d2f\u0d41. \u0d0e\u0d38\u0d4d. \u0d13\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7a \u0d2a\u0d41\u0d30\u0d41\u0d37 \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d02\u0d17\u0d3f\u0d7e \u0d15\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d40\u0d1f\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d47\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d?\r\n","option1":"\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d2b\u0d47\u0d7d \u0d28\u0d21\u0d3e\u0d7d \r\n","option2":"\u0d31\u0d4b\u0d1c\u0d7c \u0d2b\u0d46\u0d21\u0d31\u0d7c \r\n","option3":"\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7b \u0d35\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d4d\u200c\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15 \r\n","option4":"\u0d15\u0d46\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d7b \u0d06\u0d7b\u0d21\u0d47\u0d34\u0d4d\u200c\u0d38\u0d7a ","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"13","question":"\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d34\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d4a\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d35\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d2e\u0d57\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d15 \u0d05\u0d35\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d36\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d41\u0d7e\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d24\u0d4d ?\r\n","option1":"\u0d38\u0d2e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d05\u0d35\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d36\u0d02 \r\n","option2":"\u0d38\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d30 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30 \r\n","option3":"\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d05\u0d35\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d36\u0d02 \r\n","option4":"\u0d2e\u0d24\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d05\u0d35\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d36\u0d02 ","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"14","question":"\u0d38\u0d7c\u0d35\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d40\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d06\u0d30\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d \u0d13\u0d02\u0d2c\u0d41\u0d21\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d ? ","option1":"\u0d10.\u0d0e.\u0d0e\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d13\u0d2b\u0d40\u0d38\u0d7c","option2":"\u0d10.\u0d2a\u0d3f.\u0d0e\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d13\u0d2b\u0d40\u0d38\u0d7c","option3":"\u0d39\u0d48\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d1c\u0d21\u0d4d\u0d1c\u0d3f ","option4":"\u0d07\u0d35\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"15","question":"\u0d38\u0d7c\u0d35\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d47 \u0d13\u0d2b\u0d4d \u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02? ","option1":"\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d42\u0d21\u0d7d\u0d39\u0d3f","option2":"\u0d15\u0d4a\u0d7d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24","option3":"\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d02\u0d2c\u0d48","option4":"\u0d21\u0d46\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d21\u0d42\u0d7a\r\n","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"16","question":"\u0d06\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d \u0d15\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d47\u0d7d \u0d2a\u0d4a\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d7b ?\r\n","option1":"\u0d2a\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d38\u0d02\u0d30\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d15\u0d7b \r\n","option2":"\u0d17\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d30\u0d1a\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d4d \r\n","option3":"\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d27\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d35\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d15\u0d7b \r\n","option4":"\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d2d\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d38 \u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d15\u0d7b ","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"17","question":"\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d23\u0d7d\u0d37\u0d3f\u0d2a\u0d4d \u0d21\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d48\u0d7b \u0d06\u0d7b\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d31\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d47\u0d7c\u0d1a\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d46\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 ?","option1":"\u0d2e\u0d02\u0d17\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d2a\u0d41\u0d30\u0d02 ","option2":"\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d02\u0d2c\u0d48 \r\n","option3":"\u0d15\u0d4a\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3f ","option4":"\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d36\u0d3e\u0d16\u0d2a\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d23\u0d02 ","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"18","question":"\u0d15\u0d4a\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d27\u0d28\u0d41\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d24\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d2c\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d3f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d40\u0d2f\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d24 ?","option1":"NH 47","option2":"NH 49","option3":"NH 44","option4":"NH 17","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"19","question":"\u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d35\u0d7d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f \u0d28\u0d26\u0d3f ? \r\n","option1":"\u0d17\u0d02\u0d17 ","option2":"\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f ","option3":"\u0d37\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d4b\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d25\u0d4d\u200c ","option4":"\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d7a\u0d21\u0d4b\u0d35\u0d3f ","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"20","question":"\u0d28\u0d40\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d06\u0d2f\u0d4b\u0d17\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d35\u0d48\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d7c\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d7b ?\r\n","option1":"\u0d21\u0d4b. \u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d40\u0d35\u0d4d \u0d15\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d7c \r\n","option2":"\u0d05\u0d30\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d4d \u0d2a\u0d28\u0d17\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3f \r\n","option3":"\u0d21\u0d4b. \u0d2e\u0d7b\u0d2e\u0d4b\u0d39\u0d7b \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d02\u0d17\u0d4d \r\n","option4":"\u0d05\u0d2e\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d3e \u0d38\u0d46\u0d7b ","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"21","question":"\u0d39\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d05\u0d23\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d28\u0d26\u0d3f ?","option1":"\u0d2e\u0d39\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d26\u0d3f ","option2":"\u0d17\u0d4b\u0d26\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d30\u0d3f ","option3":"\u0d15\u0d43\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d23 ","option4":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d47\u0d30\u0d3f ","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"22","question":"2024 \u0d32\u0d46 \u0d12\u0d33\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d35\u0d47\u0d26\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d ?\r\n\r\n","option1":"\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d40\u0d38\u0d4d ","option2":"\u0d1f\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d4b \r\n","option3":"\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d0f\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d7d\u0d38\u0d4d \r\n","option4":"\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d4b\u0d21\u0d3f \u0d1c\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4b ","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"23","question":"\u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d2a\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d35\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d30 \u0d2a\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d \u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d15\u0d33\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d7d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d30\u0d23\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d ?\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"24","question":"\u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d0f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 [\u0d2a\u0d34\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d02 \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d35\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d35\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d02 ?\r\n","option1":"\u0d15\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d33\u0d3f \u0d35\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d35\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d02 \r\n","option2":"\u0d2a\u0d30\u0d41\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d35\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d35\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d02 \r\n","option3":"\u0d2a\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d30 \u0d35\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d35\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d02 \r\n","option4":"\u0d2a\u0d47\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7c \u0d35\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d35\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d02 ","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"25","question":"\u0d2a\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1e\u0d3e\u0d31\u0d7b \u0d31\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d\u0d35\u0d47\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 ?\r\n","option1":"\u0d1a\u0d46\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d48 \r\n","option2":"\u0d1c\u0d2f\u0d4d\u200c\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d7c \r\n","option3":"\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d02\u0d2c\u0d48 \r\n","option4":"\u0d15\u0d4a\u0d7d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24 ","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"26","question":"\u0d26\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d2d\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d7b \u0d38\u0d02\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 ?\r\n","option1":"\u0d06\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d02 \r\n","option2":"\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d02 \r\n","option3":"\u0d1c\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d41-\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d40\u0d7c \r\n","option4":"\u0d05\u0d30\u0d41\u0d23\u0d3e\u0d1a\u0d7d \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d4d ","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"27","question":"\u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d2e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d46 \u0d09\u0d2a\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d2a\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d \u0d36\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40. \u0d35\u0d46\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d28\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d21\u0d41 ?\r\n","option1":"11","option2":"12","option3":"13","option4":"14","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"28","question":"\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40\u0d2c\u0d41\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d7b \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d7c\u0d35\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d02 \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d32\u0d02?\r\n","option1":"\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d25\u0d4d\u200c ","option2":"\u0d15\u0d47\u0d26\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d25\u0d4d\u200c ","option3":"\u0d35\u0d48\u0d36\u0d3e\u0d16\u0d3f \r\n","option4":"\u0d15\u0d41\u0d36\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d17\u0d30\u0d02 ","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"29","question":"\u0d2c\u0d02\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d47\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d15\u0d1f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d7b \u0d38\u0d02\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02 ?\r\n","option1":"\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d2a\u0d41\u0d30 ","option2":"\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4b\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d02 ","option3":"\u0d2e\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d42\u0d7c \r\n","option4":"\u0d2e\u0d47\u0d18\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d2f ","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"30","question":"\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d34\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d4a\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d35\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d \"\u0d05\u0d39\u0d4b\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 \u0d1c\u0d3e\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d24 \"?","option1":"\u0d15\u0d30\u0d38\u0d47\u0d28\u0d3e ","option2":"\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d38\u0d47\u0d28 ","option3":"\u0d35\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d4b\u0d2e\u0d38\u0d47\u0d28 ","option4":"\u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d7b \u0d2a\u0d4b\u0d32\u0d40\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d47\u0d28 ","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"31","question":"\u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d46 \u0d05\u0d23\u0d41\u0d2a\u0d30\u0d40\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d23\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d ?\r\n","option1":"\u0d2a\u0d4a\u0d16\u0d4d\u200c\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7b \r\n","option2":"\u0d1c\u0d2f\u0d4d\u200c\u0d2a\u0d42\u0d7c \r\n","option3":"\u0d1c\u0d2f\u0d4d\u200c\u0d38\u0d3e\u0d7d \u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d7c \r\n","option4":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d7d\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d02 ","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"32","question":"\u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d15\u0d46 \u0d2a\u0d4b\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d7d \u0d38\u0d4b\u0d23\u0d41\u0d15\u0d33\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d0e\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d23\u0d02 ?","option1":"3","option2":"5","option3":"6","option4":"8","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"33","question":"\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d15 \u0d15\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25 \u0d26\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d02 ?\r\n","option1":"\u0d1c\u0d42\u0d7a 8 \r\n","option2":"\u0d1c\u0d42\u0d32\u0d48 21 \r\n","option3":"\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d4d 22 \r\n","option4":"\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d4d 23 ","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"34","question":"\u0d09\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d30\u0d47\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d35\u0d47\u0d28\u0d7d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d41 \u0d35\u0d40\u0d36\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d3f\u0d15 \u0d35\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d :\r\n","option1":"\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d02\u0d17\u0d4b \u0d37\u0d35\u0d7c \r\n","option2":"\u0d32\u0d42 \r\n","option3":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d7d\u0d16 \u0d36\u0d3e\u0d16\u0d3f \r\n","option4":"\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d42\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d ","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"35","question":"\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f \u0d2a\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d47\u0d24\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d46\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d46?","option1":"\u0d39\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d28 ","option2":"\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d7b ","option3":"\u0d24\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d34\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d ","option4":"\u0d32\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d40\u0d2a\u0d4d ","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"36","question":"\u0d31\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d\u0d35\u0d47 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d47\u0d37\u0d28\u0d41\u0d15\u0d33\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d15\u0d41\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1e\u0d41\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d7e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d1a\u0d42\u0d1f\u0d4d \u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d2d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d23\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d32\u0d2d\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d7b \u0d31\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d\u0d35\u0d47 \u0d2e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d02 \u0d06\u0d30\u0d02\u0d2d\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d2a\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d24\u0d3f ?\r\n","option1":"\u0d2e\u0d3e \r\n","option2":"\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30 \r\n","option3":"\u0d1c\u0d28\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d47\u0d35 \r\n","option4":"\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d2e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f \u0d38\u0d41\u0d30\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d43\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d35 \u0d2f\u0d4b\u0d1c\u0d28 ","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"37","question":"\u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d7b \u0d30\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d4d\u200c\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d2a\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d30\u0d3e\u0d02\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d25\u0d4d \u0d15\u0d4b\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d1c\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d02 ?\r\n","option1":"\u0d09\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d7c\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d4d \r\n","option2":"\u0d2e\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d4d \r\n","option3":"\u0d2c\u0d40\u0d39\u0d3e\u0d7c \r\n","option4":"\u0d17\u0d41\u0d1c\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d ","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"38","question":"\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d2a\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d24\u0d46\u0d30\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1e\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d4d , \u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d38\u0d2d\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d47\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d05\u0d02\u0d17\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d33\u0d46 \u0d28\u0d3e\u0d2e\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d7c\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d47\u0d36\u0d02 \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d21\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d05\u0d27\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d35\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d3e\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d1f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d2d\u0d30\u0d23\u0d18\u0d1f\u0d28 ?\r\n\r\n","option1":"\u0d05\u0d2f\u0d7c\u0d32\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d ","option2":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d21 \r\n","option3":"\u0d06\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d47\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d2f \r\n","option4":"\u0d31\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d2f ","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"39","question":"\u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d2c\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d4d \u0d27\u0d28 \u0d2c\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4b \u0d05\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d2f\u0d4b \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d24\u0d40\u0d30\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d06\u0d30\u0d4d ?\r\n","option1":"\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d4d\u200c\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d2a\u0d24\u0d3f \r\n","option2":"\u0d09\u0d2a\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d2a\u0d24\u0d3f \r\n","option3":"\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d4d\u200c\u0d38\u0d2d\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d4d\u200c\u0d2a\u0d40\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d7c \r\n","option4":"\u0d27\u0d28\u0d2e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f ","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"40","question":"\u0d13\u0d7c\u0d21\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d7b\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d2a\u0d41\u0d31\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7b \u0d05\u0d27\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d ?\r\n","option1":"\u0d17\u0d35\u0d7c\u0d23\u0d7c \r\n","option2":"\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d16\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f \r\n","option3":"\u0d1a\u0d40\u0d2b\u0d4d \u0d1c\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d \r\n","option4":"\u0d1a\u0d40\u0d2b\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d46\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d31\u0d3f ","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"41","question":"\u0d2e\u0d39\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d40\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d ?\r\n","option1":"\u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d17\u0d02\u0d17\u0d3e\u0d27\u0d30\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d15\u0d4d \r\n","option2":"\u0d17\u0d4b\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d15\u0d43\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d23 \u0d17\u0d4b\u0d16\u0d32\u0d46 \r\n","option3":"\u0d26\u0d3e\u0d26\u0d3e \u0d2d\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d35\u0d31\u0d4b\u0d1c\u0d3f \r\n","option4":"\u0d21\u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d42. \u0d38\u0d3f. \u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d7c\u0d1c\u0d3f ","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"42","question":"\u0d2d\u0d30\u0d23\u0d18\u0d1f\u0d28\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d2e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d46 \u0d37\u0d46\u0d21\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d42\u0d33\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d \u0d2d\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d15\u0d7e \u0d09\u0d7e\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d?\r\n","option1":"11","option2":"10","option3":"9","option4":"8","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"43","question":"\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d34\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d4a\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d35\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d26\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d3f \u0d2e\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d21\u0d32\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d7b \u0d38\u0d02\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02?\r\n","option1":"\u0d24\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d34\u0d4d\u200c\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d \r\n","option2":"\u0d15\u0d47\u0d30\u0d33\u0d02 ","option3":"\u0d15\u0d7c\u0d23\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d15 ","option4":"\u0d39\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d28","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"44","question":"\u0d27\u0d28\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d15\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d40\u0d37\u0d28\u0d46 \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d2e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f ","option2":"\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d4d\u200c\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d2a\u0d24\u0d3f \r\n","option3":"\u0d09\u0d2a\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d2a\u0d24\u0d3f \r\n","option4":"\u0d38\u0d4d\u200c\u0d2a\u0d40\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d7c ","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"45","question":"\u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d15\u0d33\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d ?\r\n","option1":"\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d47\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d \u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d13\u0d2b\u0d4d \u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f ","option2":"\u0d2a\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d2c\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d3e\u0d37\u0d23\u0d7d \u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \r\n","option3":"\u0d2b\u0d46\u0d21\u0d31\u0d7d \u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \r\n","option4":"\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d7c\u0d35\u0d4d \u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d13\u0d2b\u0d4d \u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f ","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"46","question":"\u0d15\u0d4b\u0d2e\u0d7a\u0d35\u0d46\u0d7d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d33\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d39\u0d48\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d1c\u0d21\u0d4d\u200c\u0d1c\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d2f \u0d35\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d3e?\r\n","option1":"\u0d05\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f \r\n","option2":"\u0d2a\u0d3f. \u0d1c\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e \r\n","option3":"\u0d2e\u0d47\u0d30\u0d3f \u0d2e\u0d38\u0d4d\u200c\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40\u0d7b \r\n","option4":"\u0d2e\u0d47\u0d30\u0d3f \u0d31\u0d4b\u0d2f\u0d4d ","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"47","question":"\u0d15\u0d47\u0d30\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d0f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d35\u0d1f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d47 \u0d05\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d05\u0d38\u0d02\u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d3f \u0d2e\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d21\u0d32\u0d02 ?\r\n","option1":"\u0d28\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d7b\u0d15\u0d30 ","option2":"\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d31\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d36\u0d3e\u0d32 \r\n","option3":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d7c\u0d15\u0d4b\u0d21\u0d4d ","option4":"\u0d2e\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d47\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d30\u0d02 ","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"48","question":"\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d32 \u0d38\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d26\u0d3e\u0d2f \u0d2a\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d37\u0d4d\u200c\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d23\u0d3f \u0d38\u0d2d\u0d2f\u0d4d\u200c\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d28\u0d47\u0d24\u0d43\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d7d\u0d15\u0d3f \u0d30\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d40\u0d15\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d24\u0d4d ?\r\n","option1":"\u0d38\u0d39\u0d4b\u0d26\u0d30\u0d7b \u0d05\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7b \r\n","option2":"\u0d2a\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d21\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d \u0d15\u0d46. \u0d2a\u0d3f.\u0d15\u0d31\u0d41\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7b \r\n","option3":"\u0d05\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d3f \r\n","option4":"\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d23 \u0d17\u0d41\u0d30\u0d41 ","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"49","question":"\u0d15\u0d47\u0d30\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d12\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d02 \u0d2e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d2d\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d27\u0d28\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d35\u0d15\u0d41\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f ?\r\n","option1":"\u0d1f\u0d3f. \u0d35\u0d3f. \u0d24\u0d4b\u0d2e\u0d38\u0d4d \r\n","option2":"\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f.\u0d0e.\u0d2e\u0d1c\u0d40\u0d26\u0d4d \r\n","option3":"\u0d15\u0d46.\u0d06\u0d7c. \u0d17\u0d57\u0d30\u0d3f \r\n","option4":"\u0d38\u0d3f. \u0d05\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d24\u0d2e\u0d47\u0d28\u0d4b\u0d7b ","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"50","question":"\u0d15\u0d47\u0d30\u0d33 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d28 \u0d35\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d40\u0d37\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d7c\u0d2a\u0d47\u0d34\u0d4d\u200c\u0d38\u0d7a?\r\n","option1":"\u0d0e\u0d02. \u0d15\u0d2e\u0d32\u0d02 \r\n","option2":"\u0d38\u0d41\u0d17\u0d24\u0d15\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3f \r\n","option3":"\u0d1c\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d15\u0d46.\u0d15\u0d46. \u0d09\u0d37 \r\n","option4":"\u0d1c\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d \u0d2a\u0d3f \u0d2b\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2e \u0d2c\u0d40\u0d35\u0d3f ","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"51","question":"\u0d15\u0d47\u0d30\u0d33\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d36\u0d3f\u0d36\u0d41 \u0d38\u0d57\u0d39\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d26 \u0d2a\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d ?","option1":"\u0d35\u0d46\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d42\u0d7c \r\n","option2":"\u0d28\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d36\u0d47\u0d30\u0d3f ","option3":"\u0d15\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1e\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d34\u0d3f \r\n","option4":"\u0d2a\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d7d ","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"52","question":"\u0d2a\u0d31\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d33\u0d02 \u0d35\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d43\u0d17 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d30\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d23 \u0d15\u0d47\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3f\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d ?\r\n","option1":"\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d41\u0d35\u0d28\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d2a\u0d41\u0d30\u0d02 \r\n","option2":"\u0d07\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f \r\n","option3":"\u0d35\u0d2f\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d \r\n","option4":"\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d ","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"53","question":"\u0d28\u0d46\u0d39\u0d4d\u200c\u0d31\u0d41 \u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d4b\u0d2b\u0d3f \u0d35\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33\u0d02\u0d15\u0d33\u0d3f \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d15\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d7d ?\r\n","option1":"\u0d35\u0d47\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d \r\n","option2":"\u0d05\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d3f ","option3":"\u0d2a\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d2e\u0d1f ","option4":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d02\u0d15\u0d41\u0d33\u0d02 ","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"54","question":"\u0d15\u0d4a\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3f \u0d15\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d7d \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d7c\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d23 \u0d15\u0d47\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7b \u0d38\u0d39\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d02?\r\n","option1":"\u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d7a \r\n","option2":"\u0d31\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d2f \r\n","option3":"\u0d1c\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d7b \r\n","option4":"\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d21 ","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"55","question":"\u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d7c \u0d32\u0d39\u0d33\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d2c\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f \u0d38\u0d3e\u0d2e\u0d42\u0d39\u0d3f\u0d15 \u0d2a\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d37\u0d4d\u200c\u0d15\u0d7c\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d4d?\r\n","option1":"\u0d05\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d7b\u200c\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d33\u0d3f \r\n","option2":"\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d23 \u0d17\u0d41\u0d30\u0d41 \r\n","option3":"\u0d1a\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3f \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d7e \r\n","option4":"\u0d35\u0d48\u0d15\u0d41\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d21 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d7e ","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"56","question":"\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f GST \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d02?\r\n\r\n","option1":"\u0d2b\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d7b\u0d38\u0d4d \r\n","option2":"\u0d07\u0d02\u0d17\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d ","option3":"\u0d1c\u0d7c\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d28\u0d3f \r\n","option4":"\u0d31\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d2f ","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"57","question":"'\u0d39\u0d3e\u0d7c\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d \u0d13\u0d2b\u0d4d \u0d0f\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d2f' \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d41 \u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7b\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d38\u0d28\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d41\u0d30\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d32\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d05\u0d2f\u0d7d\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d1c\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d33\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d30\u0d02\u0d2d\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d?\r\n","option1":"\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40\u0d32\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15 \r\n","option2":"\u0d05\u0d2b\u0d4d\u200c\u0d17\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d25\u0d3e\u0d7b \r\n","option3":"\u0d2d\u0d42\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3e\u0d7b \r\n","option4":"\u0d28\u0d47\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3e\u0d7e ","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"58","question":"\u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d07\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d47\u0d7d \u0d38\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d7c\u0d36\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d7b \u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d27\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d2e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f?\r\n","option1":"\u0d1c\u0d35\u0d39\u0d7c\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d7d \u0d28\u0d46\u0d39\u0d4d\u200c\u0d31\u0d41 \r\n","option2":"\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d7d \u0d2c\u0d39\u0d26\u0d42\u0d7c \u0d36\u0d3e\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d3f \r\n","option3":"\u0d21\u0d4b. \u0d2e\u0d7b\u0d2e\u0d4b\u0d39\u0d7b \u0d38\u0d3f\u0d02\u0d17\u0d4d \r\n","option4":"\u0d28\u0d30\u0d47\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d2e\u0d4b\u0d26\u0d3f ","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"59","question":"\u0d2a\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d2e\u0d18\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d0f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d35\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d09\u0d2f\u0d30\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d42\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d15\u0d4a\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d3f?\r\n","option1":"\u0d06\u0d28\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d3f \r\n","option2":"\u0d28\u0d40\u0d32\u0d17\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d3f ","option3":"\u0d05\u0d17\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2e\u0d32 ","option4":"\u0d2e\u0d39\u0d3e\u0d2c\u0d32\u0d47\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d7c ","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"60","question":"\u0d2a\u0d4b\u0d7c\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d41\u0d17\u0d40\u0d38\u0d41\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d17\u0d4b\u0d35 \u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d1f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d7b \u0d35\u0d47\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f \u0d07\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d28\u0d1f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d38\u0d48\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d15 \u0d13\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d31\u0d47\u0d37\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d2a\u0d47\u0d30\u0d46\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d?\r\n","option1":"\u0d13\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d31\u0d47\u0d37\u0d7b \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d1c\u0d2f\u0d4d \r\n","option2":"\u0d13\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d31\u0d47\u0d37\u0d7b \u0d35\u0d1c\u0d4d\u0d30 \r\n","option3":"\u0d13\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d31\u0d47\u0d37\u0d7b \u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d42 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d3e\u0d7c \r\n","option4":"\u0d13\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d31\u0d47\u0d37\u0d7b \u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d24\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d7c ","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"61","question":"The word nearest in meaning to the word 'Alert' is","option1":"energetic","option2":"observant","option3":"watchful","option4":"intelligent","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"62","question":"Which of the following is the word opposite in meaning to the word 'Assemble'?","option1":"dispose","option2":"disperse","option3":"dispense","option4":"displace","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"63","question":"Choose the incorrectly spelt word:","option1":"Accommodate","option2":"Accumulate","option3":"Recommend","option4":"Vaccation","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"64","question":"Find out the correct sentence:","option1":"Each of the boy are clever","option2":"Each of the boys were clever","option3":"Each of the boys is clever","option4":"Each of the boys have clever","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"65","question":"\"He plays piano\" is an example of:","option1":"imperative sentence","option2":"interrogative sentence","option3":"declarative sentence","option4":"exclamatory sentence","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"66","question":"The baby walked slowly. In this sentence 'slowly' is:","option1":"adjective","option2":"adverb","option3":"pronoun","option4":"noun","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"67","question":"Passive voice of \"He has drawn two pictures\" is","option1":"Two pictures have been drawn by him","option2":"Two pictures has been drawn by him","option3":"Two pictures had been drawn by him","option4":"Two pictures had being drawn by him","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"68","question":"The reported speech of \"Mary said, I am watching television\" is:","option1":"Mary said that she is watching television","option2":"Mary said that she has been watching television","option3":"Mary said that she watches television","option4":"Mary said that she was watching television","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"69","question":"Pick out the singular form from the given words:","option1":"Data","option2":"Mice","option3":"Teeth","option4":"Fungus","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"70","question":"Which of the following is a one word of \"A government by a King or a Queen\"?","option1":"Monarchy","option2":"Autocracy","option3":"Aristocracy","option4":"Democracy","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"71","question":"Neither his brother nor his sister_____ wise.","option1":"are","option2":"were","option3":"has","option4":"is","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"72","question":"The empty mountain regions without trees are an awful:","option1":"site","option2":"sight","option3":"cite","option4":"seen","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"73","question":"Replace the word in bold letters with the right phrase chosen from those given below: Abraham Lincoln wanted to ABOLISH slavery in USA.","option1":"put and end to","option2":"put up with","option3":"put on","option4":"put up","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"74","question":"Gifty is ______ than Geetha.","option1":"young","option2":"youngest","option3":"younger","option4":"eldest","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"75","question":"We expect _____ official enquiry into the incident.","option1":"the","option2":"an","option3":"a","option4":"some","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"76","question":"Chithra dances well _____ ?","option1":"does she?","option2":"doesn't she?","option3":"did she?","option4":"didn't she?","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"77","question":"Rani is holding a vase ______ her hand.","option1":"on","option2":"under","option3":"upon","option4":"in","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"78","question":"Children ______ to school every day.","option1":"go","option2":"goes","option3":"going","option4":"went","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"79","question":"Shakespeare is the _____ Dramatist in English.","option1":"great","option2":"greater","option3":"greatest","option4":"more greath","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"80","question":"He has been speaking continuously _____ 5'O clock.","option1":"since","option2":"for","option3":"from","option4":"to","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"81","question":"\u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d15\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d28\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d41 \u0d2e\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d35\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d4b\u0d7e \u0d2e\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d42\u0d7c \u0d38\u0d42\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d42\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d07\u0d1f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d15\u0d4b\u0d23\u0d33\u0d35\u0d4d \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30?\r\n","option1":"90","option2":"105","option3":"120","option4":"160","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"82","question":"441:462::841:x \u0d06\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d7d x \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30?","option1":"800","option2":"830","option3":"860","option4":"870","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"83","question":"\u0d05\u0d7b\u0d37\u0d3e \u0d35\u0d40\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d41\u0d02 3 \u0d15\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d2e\u0d40\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d7c \u0d24\u0d46\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d24\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d7c\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d4d 4 \u0d15\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d2e\u0d40\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d7c \u0d15\u0d3f\u0d34\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d \u0d15\u0d4b\u0d33\u0d47\u0d1c\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d. \u0d0e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d35\u0d40\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d4b\u0d33\u0d47\u0d1c\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d47\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d46\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d15\u0d41\u0d31\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1e \u0d26\u0d42\u0d30\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30?","option1":"5","option2":"7","option3":"3.5","option4":"12","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"84","question":"# \u0d17\u0d41\u0d23\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 @ \u0d39\u0d30\u0d23\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 * \u0d38\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d32\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 % \u0d35\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d35\u0d15\u0d32\u0d28\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d42\u0d1a\u0d3f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d3e\u0d7d 16@2*3#4%10 \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30?","option1":"34","option2":"4","option3":"-2","option4":"10","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"85","question":"\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d34\u0d46\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d35\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d15\u0d42\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"57","option2":"59","option3":"61","option4":"67","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"86","question":"62,55.48, ........ \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d36\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d46\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d2a\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d2e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d46 \u0d2a\u0d26\u0d02 \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"0","option2":"1","option3":"-1","option4":"-2","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"87","question":"\u0d2a\u0d41\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d4a\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d2e\u0d4a\u0d2c\u0d48\u0d7d \u0d2b\u0d4b\u0d7a \u0d35\u0d3e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d2f 15,000 \u0d30\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d35\u0d3e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d2a\u0d34\u0d2f \u0d2b\u0d4b\u0d7a 15% \u0d28\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d41. \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30 \u0d30\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d \u0d2a\u0d34\u0d2f \u0d2b\u0d4b\u0d7a \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"12,000","option2":"12,750","option3":"2,250","option4":"12,500","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"88","question":"\u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d16\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d0e\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d1f\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d4d 8.2 \u0d06\u0d23\u0d4d. \u0d38\u0d02\u0d16\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"1.025","option2":"1.250","option3":"65.006","option4":"64.016","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"89","question":"\u0d2a\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d41 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d16\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d15\u0d33\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d36\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d36\u0d30\u0d3f 125 \u0d06\u0d23\u0d4d. \u0d07\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d28\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d16\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d12\u0d34\u0d3f\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d4b\u0d7e \u0d36\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d36\u0d30\u0d3f 118 \u0d06\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d0e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d12\u0d34\u0d3f\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d24\u0d3e\u0d34\u0d46\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d38\u0d02\u0d16\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d ?","option1":"1062","option2":"7","option3":"118","option4":"188","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"90","question":"\u0d05\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d3f\u0d7b 300 \u0d15\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d2e\u0d40\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d7c \u0d26\u0d42\u0d30\u0d02 \u0d36\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d36\u0d30\u0d3f 40 \u0d15\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d2e\u0d40\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d7c \u0d35\u0d47\u0d17\u0d24\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d2c\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d38\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30 \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d41.\u0d36\u0d30\u0d3e\u0d36\u0d30\u0d3f 50 \u0d15\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4b\u0d2e\u0d40\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d7c \u0d35\u0d47\u0d17\u0d24\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d31\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d41 \u0d07\u0d24\u0d47 \u0d26\u0d42\u0d30\u0d02 \u0d38\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d24\u0d46\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30 \u0d38\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d02 \u0d32\u0d3e\u0d2d\u0d3f\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d41 \u0d15\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d41\u0d02?","option1":"75 \u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d ","option2":"90 \u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d ","option3":"60 \u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d ","option4":"80 \u0d2e\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d4d ","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"91","question":"\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d4d \u0d2a\u0d47\u0d7c \u0d1a\u0d47\u0d7c\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d4d \u0d12\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d26\u0d3f\u0d35\u0d38\u0d02\u0d15\u0d4a\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d \u0d24\u0d40\u0d7c\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d1c\u0d4b\u0d32\u0d3f \u0d06\u0d31\u0d4d \u0d26\u0d3f\u0d35\u0d38\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d4a\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d \u0d24\u0d40\u0d7c\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d23\u0d2e\u0d46\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30 \u0d1c\u0d4b\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d30\u0d46\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d42\u0d1f\u0d3f \u0d15\u0d42\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d24\u0d32\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d35\u0d47\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d35\u0d30\u0d41\u0d02?","option1":"2","option2":"4","option3":"6","option4":"8","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"92","question":"\u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d38\u0d02\u0d16\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 15% \u0d06\u0d23\u0d4d 900?","option1":"135","option2":"13500","option3":"60000","option4":"6000","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"93","question":"\u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d1a\u0d24\u0d41\u0d30\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d28\u0d40\u0d33\u0d02 \u0d28\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d35\u0d40\u0d24\u0d3f \u0d2a\u0d15\u0d41\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d15\u0d41\u0d31\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d15\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 \u0d1a\u0d46\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d7d \u0d32\u0d2d\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d2a\u0d41\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d24\u0d41\u0d30\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d40\u0d7c\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d23\u0d02 \u0d06\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d1a\u0d24\u0d41\u0d30\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d38\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d40\u0d7c\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d23\u0d35\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d41\u0d02?\r\n","option1":"\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d1f\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d35\u0d7c\u0d26\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d02 \r\n","option2":"\u0d2a\u0d15\u0d41\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f \u0d15\u0d41\u0d31\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d02 \r\n","option3":"\u0d30\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4d \u0d2e\u0d1f\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d41\u0d02 \r\n","option4":"\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d4a\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d41\u0d02 ","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"94","question":"15:18=x:144 \u0d06\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d7d x \u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d32 \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30?","option1":"60","option2":"72","option3":"90","option4":"120","answer":"4"},{"question_no":"95","question":"2008 \u0d32\u0d46 \u0d31\u0d3f\u0d2a\u0d4d\u0d2a\u0d2c\u0d4d\u0d32\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d26\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d36\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d34\u0d4d\u0d1a \u0d06\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d46\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d35\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d26\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d02 \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d26\u0d3f\u0d35\u0d38\u0d02 \u0d06\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d02?\r\n","option1":"\u0d2c\u0d41\u0d27\u0d7b \r\n","option2":"\u0d35\u0d4d\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d34\u0d02 \r\n","option3":"\u0d35\u0d46\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33\u0d3f \r\n","option4":"\u0d36\u0d28\u0d3f ","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"96","question":"\u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d2b\u0d4b\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d4b\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40\u0d2f\u0d46 \u0d1a\u0d42\u0d23\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3e\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d3f \u0d0e\u0d7d\u0d26\u0d4b \u0d2a\u0d31\u0d1e\u0d4d\u0d1e\u0d41. \u0d07\u0d35\u0d30\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d05\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d38\u0d39\u0d4b\u0d26\u0d30\u0d7b \u0d0e\u0d7b\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d05\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d1f\u0d46 \u0d05\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1b\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d12\u0d30\u0d47 \u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d2e\u0d15\u0d28\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d. \u0d0e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d0e\u0d32\u0d4d\u0d26\u0d4b\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d08 \u0d38\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d40\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d41\u0d33\u0d4d\u0d33 \u0d2c\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d27\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d23\u0d4d?","option1":"\u0d05\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e \r\n","option2":"\u0d38\u0d39\u0d4b\u0d26\u0d30\u0d3f ","option3":"\u0d2e\u0d41\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d36\u0d4d\u0d36\u0d3f \r\n","option4":"\u0d05\u0d2e\u0d4d\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f ","answer":"2"},{"question_no":"97","question":"15,20,26,33,41,.....\u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d36\u0d4d\u0d30\u0d46\u0d23\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d32\u0d46 \u0d05\u0d1f\u0d41\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24 \u0d38\u0d02\u0d16\u0d4d\u0d2f \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d02?","option1":"50","option2":"49","option3":"52","option4":"57","answer":"1"},{"question_no":"98","question":"BREAK \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d35\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d4b\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d30\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7d ASDBJ \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d46\u0d34\u0d41\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d2f\u0d3e\u0d7d SOLAR \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28 \u0d35\u0d3e\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d46 \u0d15\u0d4b\u0d21\u0d4d \u0d30\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d02?","option1":"RPKBS","option2":"TPMBS","option3":"RPKBQ","option4":"TPKBQ","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"99","question":"\u0d24\u0d3e\u0d34\u0d46\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d3f\u0d30\u0d3f\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d41\u0d28\u0d4d\u0d28\u0d35\u0d2f\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d15\u0d42\u0d1f\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d2a\u0d46\u0d1f\u0d3e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d24\u0d24\u0d4d \u0d0f\u0d24\u0d4d?","option1":"1000","option2":"8000","option3":"16000","option4":"27000","answer":"3"},{"question_no":"100","question":"\u0d2c\u0d3e\u0d2c\u0d41 1500 \u0d30\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d12\u0d30\u0d41 \u0d35\u0d3e\u0d1a\u0d4d\u0d1a\u0d4d \u0d35\u0d3e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d19\u0d3f 1320 \u0d30\u0d42\u0d2a\u0d2f\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d4d \u0d35\u0d3f\u0d31\u0d4d\u0d31\u0d41. \u0d0e\u0d19\u0d4d\u0d15\u0d3f\u0d7d \u0d28\u0d37\u0d4d\u0d1f\u0d02 \u0d0e\u0d24\u0d4d\u0d30 \u0d36\u0d24\u0d2e\u0d3e\u0d28\u0d02?","option1":"10%","option2":"12%","option3":"14%","option4":"16%","answer":"2"}]},"code":"100"}
